A Finding Aid to the Dorothy Weiss Gallery Records, circa 1964-2001 (bulk 1984-2000), in the Archives of American Art AAA.doroweig
Archives of American Art
- Artist Files, circa 1964-2001; Series 1; 17.5 Linear feet Boxes 1-18, OV 21
  - Turner, Robert (Box 14)
    - Printed Material, 1979-1999 (Box 14, Folder 15-16)
    - Photographic Material, circa 1980-1991 (Box 14, Folder 17)
  - Unterseher, Chris, General, 1981-1999 (Box 14, Folder 18)
  - Van Cline, Mary, General, circa 1987-1988 (Box 14, Folder 19)
  - Van Eimeren, Eric, General, circa 1997-1999 (Box 14, Folder 20)
  - Van Nostrand, General, circa 1995-1997 (Box 14, Folder 21)
  - Vikova, Jindra, General, circa 1990-1993 (Box 14, Folder 22)
  - Walker, Jamie (Box 14)
    - Announcements and Press Releases, DW Gallery, 1984-1996 (Box 14, Folder 23)
    - Correspondence, 1982-2001 (Box 14, Folder 24-25)
    - Printed Material, 1984-1998 (Box 14, Folder 26)
    - Photograph of Walker, circa 1986 (Box 14, Folder 27)
    - Photographic Material, circa 1980s-1990s (Box 14, Folder 28-31)
  - Warashina, Patti, Printed Material, 1983 (Box 14, Folder 32)
  - Watkins, James (Box 14)
    - General, 1985-1997 (Box 14, Folder 33)
    - Photographic Material, circa 1990-1996 (Box 14, Folder 34)
  - Weber, Mike, General, 1995-1996 (Box 14, Folder 35)
  - Weiss, Dick, General, 1996-1998 (Box 14, Folder 36)
  - Welsh, Stan (Box 14)
    - Announcements and Press Releases, DW Gallery, 1984-1995 (Box 14, Folder 37)
    - Correspondence, 1984-1998 (Box 14, Folder 38)
    - Printed Material, 1985-1999 (Box 15, Folder 1)
    - Photographic Material, circa 1984-1995 (Box 15, Folder 2)
  - Williams, Neil (Box 15)
    - General, 1983-1997 (Box 15, Folder 3)
    - Photograph of Williams?, 1990? (Box 15, Folder 4)
    - Photographic Material, circa 1983-1990 (Box 15, Folder 5)
  - Winkler, Allan (Box 15)
    - General, 1981-1991 (Box 15, Folder 6)
    - Photographs of Winkler, 1985 (Box 15, Folder 7)
    - Photographic Material, circa 1981-1991 (Box 15, Folder 8)
  - Wolf (Wärff), Ann, General, 1989-1992 (Box 15, Folder 9)
  - Wolkow, Lisa, General, circa 1986-1999 (Box 15, Folder 10)
  - Won, Kyung Hwan, General, circa 1998-1999 (Box 15, Folder 11)
  - Won Lee, Jae, General, circa 1994-1998 (Box 15, Folder 12)
  - Wood, Beatrice, General, 1989, 1999 (Box 15, Folder 13)
  - Wyner, Sandra, General, 1981-1990 (Box 15, Folder 14)
  - Young, Sara, General, 1985, 1991 (Box 15, Folder 15)
  - Yuh, Sun-Koo, General, 1998-1999 (Box 15, Folder 16)
  - Zimmerman, Arnold, General, 1984-1999 (Box 15, Folder 17)
  - Slides (Box 16)
    - Abilgard, Mark, circa 1988-1999; (slide box 1) (Box 16)
    - Adams, Hank Murta, circa 1980-1989; (slide box 1) (Box 16)
    - Aebersold, Jane Ford, circa 1982-1987; (slide box 1-2) (Box 16)
    - Anderson, Daniel, 1989-1994; (slide box 2) (Box 16)
    - Autio, Rudy, circa 1975-1997; (slide box 2-3) (Box 16)
    - Berman, Harriete Estel, circa 1982-1991; (slide box 3) (Box 16)
    - Blakely, Ellen, circa 1982-1986; (slide box 3-4) (Box 16)
    - Brice, Daniel, circa 1994-1999; (slide box 4) (Box 16)
    - Castle, Wendell, circa 1988-1996; (slide box 4) (Box 16)
    - Chamberlin, Scott, circa 1981-2000; (slide box 4-5) (Box 16)
    - Christenson, Ann, circa 1990-1997; (slide box 5) (Box 16)
    - Clayman, Daniel, circa 1987-1989; (slide box 5) (Box 16)
    - Corcoran, Annette, 1981-1998; (slide box 6-7) (Box 16)
    - Cornelius, Philip, circa 1981-1999; (slide box 7) (Box 16)
    - Cox, Kris, circa 1989-1995; (slide box 7) (Box 16)
    - de la Torre, Einar and Jamex, undated; (slide box 8) (Box 16)
    - de Swart, Peter, 1989-1995; (slide box 8) (Box 16)
    - Dickey, Kim, circa 1998; (slide box 8) (Box 16)
    - Di Pasqua, Paul, 1989-1993; (slide box 8) (Box 16)
    - Duckworth, Ruth, circa 1976-1994; (slide box 8-9) (Box 16)
    - Earl, Jack, circa 1987-1996; (slide box 9) (Box 16)
    - Ennis, Elizabeth, circa 1994-1997; (slide box 9) (Box 16)
    - Eslick, Susan, circa 1980; (slide box 9) (Box 16)
    - Federighi, Christine, circa 1979-1984; (slide box 9-10) (Box 16)
    - Fletcher, Sean A., 1996-1997; (slide box 10) (Box 16)
    - Frey, Barbara L., circa 1990-1994; (slide box 10) (Box 16)
    - Fritz, Donald C., circa 1988-1989; (slide box 10) (Box 16)
    - Furman, David, circa 1990-1992; (slide box 10-11) (Box 16)
    - Gill, John, circa 1981-1994; (slide box 11) (Box 16)
    - Hafner, Dorothy, circa 1980-1986; (slide box 11) (Box 16)
    - Heikoop, Govert, 1995-1998; (slide box 11) (Box 16)
    - Hepburn, Tony, circa 1978-1994; (slide box 12) (Box 16)
    - Hilferty, Patrick, circa 1990-1997; (slide box 12) (Box 16)
    - Hobson, Charles, circa 1990-1997; (slide box 12-13) (Box 16)
    - Huff, Jason, circa 1999; (slide box 13) (Box 16)
    - Irwin, Jeff, circa 1992-1997; (slide box 13) (Box 16)
    - Isupov, Sergei, circa 1996-2000; (slide box 13) (Box 16)
    - Iwata, Kiyomi, circa 1992-1993; (slide box 13) (Box 16)
    - Jacques, Frank, circa 1998; (slide box 13-14) (Box 16)
    - Kaneko, Jun, 1982-1998; (slide box 14) (Box 16)
    - Kehlmann, Robert, circa 1989-1992; (slide box 14 (Box 16)
    - Koblitz, Karen, 1980-1985; (slide box 14) (Box 16)
    - Koblitz, Karen, 1980-1985; (slide box 15) (Box 17)
    - Kovatch, Ron, circa 1987-1989; (slide box 15) (Box 17)
    - Krusoe, Sana, circa 1985-1993; (slide box 15) (Box 17)
    - LaBianca, Lawrence, circa 1992-1999; (slide box 15-16) (Box 17)
    - Lancet, Mark, circa 1994-1997; (slide box 16) (Box 17)
    - Lastomirsky, Geo, 1989-1998; (slide box 16) (Box 17)
    - Leedy, Jim, circa 1986-1993; (slide box 16) (Box 17)
    - Lindquist, Mark, 1989-1992; (slide box 16-17) (Box 17)
    - Lucero, Michael, circa 1981-1999; (slide box 17) (Box 17)
    - Mace, Flora and Joey Kirkpatrick, circa 1989; (slide box 17) (Box 17)
    - Mangus, Kirk, circa 1979-1997; (slide box 17-18) (Box 17)
    - Marak, Louis, 1980-1989; (slide box 18) (Box 17)
    - Marioni, Paul, circa 1987-1998; (slide box 18) (Box 17)
    - Marquis, Richard, circa 1978-1998; (slide box 18) (Box 17)
    - Massaro, Karen, circa 1994-1999; (slide box 18) (Box 17)
    - Mathieu, Paul, circa 1984-1990; (slide box 19) (Box 17)
    - Matthews, Kazuko Kayasuga, circa 1983-1992; (slide box 19) (Box 17)
    - Matuszewski, Gloria, circa 1993-1997; (slide box 19) (Box 17)
    - Mayeri, Beverly, circa 1978-1999; (slide box 19-20) (Box 17)
    - McBride, Kathryn, circa 1984-1999; (slide box 20) (Box 17)
    - Milnes, Robert, circa 1989-1998; (slide box 20) (Box 17)
    - Miyata, Masako, circa 1983-1997; (slide box 20) (Box 17)
    - Mizuno, Keisuke, circa 1997-1999; (slide box 20) (Box 17)
    - Montgomery, Steven, circa 1996-1999; (slide box 21) (Box 17)
    - Morris, James, circa 1983-1996; (slide box 21) (Box 17)
    - Morris, William, circa 1989-1997; (slide box 21) (Box 17)
    - Mosman, Timothy, circa 1987-1989; (slide box 21) (Box 17)
    - Musler, Jay, circa 1983-1998; (slide box 21-22) (Box 17)
    - Olivier, Diane, circa 1984-1991; (slide box 22) (Box 17)
    - Patti, Thomas, circa 1977-1984; (slide box 22) (Box 17)
    - Pearson, Todd, circa 1984-1994; (slide box 22) (Box 17)
    - Peet, Anne, circa 1997; (slide box 22) (Box 17)
    - Perkins, Flo, circa 1980-1989; (slide box 23) (Box 17)
    - Podmore, Amy, circa 1984-1998; (slide box 23) (Box 17)
    - Popelka, Jeremy, circa 1994-1996; (slide box 23) (Box 17)
    - Powers, Pike, circa 1989-1994; (slide box 24) (Box 17)
    - Quinn, Jeanne, circa 1997-1999; (slide box 24) (Box 17)
    - Rainey, Clifford, circa 1993-1997; (slide box 24) (Box 17)
    - Reitz, Donald, 1989; (slide box 24) (Box 17)
    - Rice, Jacqueline, circa 1982-1990; (slide box 24-25) (Box 17)
    - Ritchie, Gail, circa 1981-1995; (slide box 25) (Box 17)
    - Roberts, Amy, circa 1984-1985; (slide box 25) (Box 17)
    - Roberts, Gregory, circa 1991-1998; (slide box 25) (Box 17)
    - Rohlfing, John G., circa 1985-1997; (slide box 25-26) (Box 17)
    - Rosdol, Leslie, circa 1987-1995; (slide box 26) (Box 17)
    - Samios, William, circa 1994-1998; (slide box 26) (Box 17)
    - Sasaki, Hitoshi, circa 1982-1986; (slide box 26) (Box 17)
    - Savage, Juta, circa 1985-1990; (slide box 26) (Box 17)
    - Scanga, Italo, circa 1981-1996; (slide box 26-27) (Box 17)
    - Schacter, Mayer, circa 1984; (slide box 27) (Box 17)
    - Scoon, Thomas, circa 1989, 1992; (slide box 27) (Box 17)
    - Sedestrom, Robert, circa 1992-1993; (slide box 27) (Box 17)
    - Shay, Robert, circa 1983-1988; (slide box 27) (Box 17)
    - Silliman, Christopher, circa 1989-1998; (slide box 27-28) (Box 17)
    - Simon, Sandy, circa 1986-1997; (slide box 28) (Box 17)
    - Slusky, Joe, circa 1969-1990; (slide box 28) (Box 17)
    - Smith, Barbara Bell, circa 1984-1991; (slide box 28) (Box 17)
    - Sperry, Robert, circa 1981-1991; (slide box 28) (Box 17)
    - Statom, Therman, circa 1988-1999; (slide box 28) (Box 17)
    - Stern, Melissa, circa 1985-1987; (slide box 28) (Box 17)
    - Stewart, William, circa 1994-1998; (slide box 28-29) (Box 17)
    - Strasser, Dharma, circa 1997-1998; (slide box 29) (Box 17)
    - Sugiyama, Michio, circa 1983-1991; (slide box 29) (Box 17)
    - Takayama-Ogawa, Joan, circa 1991-1997; (slide box 29) (Box 17)
    - Tarantino, Claudia, circa 1994-1999; (slide box 29) (Box 17)
    - Taylor, Yoshio, circa 1983-1993; (slide box 29) (Box 17)
    - Terestman, Julie, circa 1989-1990; (slide box 29) (Box 17)
    - Thayer, Susan, circa 1995; (slide box 29) (Box 17)
    - Tsutsumi, Nobuko, circa 1994; (slide box 29-30) (Box 17)
    - Turner, Robert, circa 1985-1991; (slide box 30) (Box 17)
    - Walker, Jamie, circa 1983-1999; (slide box 30) (Box 17)
    - Watkins, James, circa 1982-1986; (slide box 30) (Box 17)
    - Williams, Neil, circa 1980-1992; (slide box 30) (Box 17)
    - Young, Sara, circa 1988-1991; (slide box 30) (Box 17)
    - Slide Transparency Duplicates (Box 18)
  - Oversized Artist Files (Box OV 21)
    Includes files on Tony Hepburn, William Hunt, and Kiyomi Iwata.
- Exhibition Files, 1979-1999; Series 2; 0.75 Linear feet Box 19
  This series contains records of approximately twenty-five group exhibitions held at the gallery. Files typically contain announcements, press releases, correspondence with participating artists, price lists, and photographs of artwork. Researchers should note that records of other exhibitions can be found in the artist files.
  For several exhibitions, such as the Alfred Show (1989), and some of the New Glass exhibitions and Teapot Invitationals, Weiss requested that participants submit black and white sketches, rather than photographs of artwork, for the exhibition announcements. She asked that the sketches "suggest the character and spirit of the work" to be included in the exhibition. Many of these original black and white drawings, with accompanying letters from the artists, can be found in this series. One oversized letter with accompanying teapot drawings by Juta Savage, is housed in Series 1: Artist Files, and can be found in OV 21.
  Files are chronologically by date of exhibition which appears in parentheses after the title and is followed by span dates for the folder. Some files contain records of several exhibitions of the same title over a period of years, for which no specific exhibition years are given. These folders are placed at the beginning of the series. Within folders, material is generally arranged chronologically. However, in cases where the gallery collected records relating to individual artists in a single exhibition, material is arranged alphabetically by artist and then chronologically.
  - Introductions, 1985-1997 (Box 19, Folder 1)
  - New Work for the New Year, 1988-1990 (Box 19, Folder 2)
  - New Forms In Glass - A Series of Three Exhibitions (1981), 1979-1982 (Box 19, Folder 3)
  - West Coast Glass (1982), circa 1981-1982 (Box 19, Folder 4-5)
  - Teapot Invitational (1984), 1982-1984 (Box 19, Folder 6-7)
  - Glass Sculpture: Five Artists (1985), circa 1985-1987 (Box 19, Folder 8-9)
  - Teapot Invitational (1985, 1986) (Box 19, Folder 10)
  - British Ceramics (1986), circa 1983-1992 (Box 19, Folder 11-13)
  - New Glass (1987), circa 1985-1988 (Box 19, Folder 14-15)
    Includes illustrated letter from Walter Lieberman.
  - The Alfred Show (1989), 1987-1989 (Box 19, Folder 16-17)
  - New Glass (1989), 1989-1990 (Box 19, Folder 18)
  - Teapot Invitational (1990) (Box 19, Folder 19)
  - Sculpture (1991), 1990-1991 (Box 19, Folder 20)
  - Teapot Invitational (1991, 1992), circa 1987-1992 (Box 19, Folder 21)
  - Glass Invitational (1994), circa 1991-1995 (Box 19, Folder 22)
  - Teapot Invitational (1994, 1996, 1997, 1998), 1994-1998 (Box 19, Folder 23)
  - Potent Images - Figurative Clay Sculpture (1998) (Box 19, Folder 24)
  - The Dimensional Canvas - Painted Studio Glass (1998), circa 1995-1998 (Box 19, Folder 25)
  - Important Works in Clay and Glass (1999) (Box 19, Folder 26)
- Subject Files, 1983-2000; Series 3; 0.45 Linear feet Boxes 19-20
  The subject files that comprise this series include general correspondence concerning gallery activities arranged by type of client, documentation of outgoing and returned loans, and records relating to several projects involving other institutions in which the gallery was involved. The Chicago Art Fair folder contains photographs of Dorothy Weiss Gallery installations at the Fair.
  Records are arranged alphabetically by subject.
  - Advertisements, 1985-1994 (Box 19, Folder 27)
  - American Craft Museum and Council, 1983-1996 (Box 19, Folder 28)
  - Chicago Art Fair, 1987-1993 (Box 19, Folder 29)
  - Correspondence, Art Consultants, 1990-1997 (Box 19, Folder 30)
  - Correspondence, Corporate, 1986-1995 (Box 19, Folder 31)
  - Correspondence, Foreign, 1992-2000 (Box 19, Folder 32)
  - Correspondence, Miscellaneous, 1985-1998 (Box 19, Folder 33)
  - Correspondence, Twigg-Smith, 1988-1992 (Box 19, Folder 34)
  - Loans for Exhibitions, 1984-1996 (Box 19, Folder 35-37)
  - Loans Returned, 1982-1997 (Box 20, Folder 1-3)
  - National Museum of History, Taiwan (Marvin Fang), 1992-1995, undated (Box 20, Folder 4)
  - San Francisco Craft and Folk Art Museum, 1995-1998 (Box 20, Folder 5)
  - San Francisco International Airport, 1999-2000 (Box 20, Folder 6)
  - Scripps Ceramic Annual (Beveryly Mayeri and Wouter Dam), 1998-1999 (Box 20, Folder 7)
  - Taipei Fine Arts Museum, 1984-1985 (Box 20, Folder 8)
  - The Office (Kiyoji Tsuji), 1990-1999 (Box 20, Folder 9)